const e="crk",o=200,s=50,a=[{id:197,question:"At the time of creation, the river that flowed out of Eden to water the garden divided into",option:{a:"Pishon, Hauijah, Gihon and Tigris",b:"Tigris, Cush, Assune and Hauijah",c:"Pishon, Tigris, Gihon and Euphrates",d:"Euphrates, Gihon, Assyna and Tigris"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:198,question:"During the creative activity of God, He made the beasts",option:{a:"in His own image",b:"to multiply on the earth",c:"according to their kinds",d:"to serve the needs of man"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:199,question:"“Two nations are in your womb, and two peoples born of you shall be divided”. The two people are",option:{a:"Moses and Jacob",b:"Jacob and Benjamin",c:"Esau and Ishmael",d:"Esau and Jacob"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:200,question:"Moses was nursed by",option:{a:"Pharaoh’s daughter",b:"Rachael",c:"his mother",d:"Rebecca"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:201,question:"The name Ichabod means",option:{a:"Yahweh is God",b:"beloved of  Yahweh",c:"I have asked him from the Lord",d:"the glory has departed from Israel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:202,question:"When Saul and his troops came after David in the wilderness of Ziph, David and Abishai went to Saul’s camp 		to",option:{a:"slay him",b:"surprise him",c:"capture him alive",d:"dialogue with him"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:203,question:"Saul’s death on Mount Gilboa was in consequence of his",option:{a:"sin of disobedience",b:"resorting to the witch of Endor",c:"loss of confidence in David",d:"armour bearer’s obedience"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:204,question:"Naboth would not give the vineyard to Ahab because it was",option:{a:"under cultivation",b:"inherited from his father",c:"better than Ahab’s offer",d:"undervalued by the king"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:205,question:"A good example of parental responsibility was demonstrated by",option:{a:"Samuel",b:"Eli",c:"David",d:"Asa"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:206,question:"When God said to Solomon, “Ask what I shall give you”, he requested for",option:{a:"long life and prosperity",b:"power and assistance against his enemies",c:"peace and understanding to serve God",d:"wisdom and understanding to serve the people"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:207,question:"The remote cause of the fall of Jerusalem was",option:{a:"Josiah’s death at the battle of Megiddo",b:"the military might of Israel’s enemies",c:"the sins of Manasseh, the king",d:"Judah’s with holding of tribute to Nebuchadnezzar"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:208,question:"Nebuchadnezzar punished those who refused to worship the golden image by throwing them into",option:{a:"the River Nile",b:"the rivers of  Babylon",c:"a furnace",d:"a lion’s den"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:209,question:"The wife of Hosea was called",option:{a:"Gomer",b:"B . Rahab",c:"Jael",d:"Hagar"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:210,question:"As a reward for their faith, Shadrach, Meshack and Abednego were",option:{a:"asked to return to Jerusalem",b:"granted respectable positions",c:"offered money by the king",d:"made to praise Yahweh"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:211,question:"Who among the prophets was referred to as a prophet of doom?",option:{a:"Isaiah",b:"Ezekiel",c:"Amos",d:"Jeremiah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:212,question:"Jonah typified Jesus Christ when he",option:{a:"surrendered himself to be swallowed by the fish",b:"offered to lose his life that others might be saved",c:"rejected the message of God",d:"announced destruction for the Ninevites"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:213,question:"The message of Amos was mainly about",option:{a:"the love of God",b:"man’s response to God’s love.",c:"the holiness of God",d:"social justice"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:214,question:"Before Joseph and Mary came together, she was found to be with a child",option:{a:"to be called Jesus",b:"of the Holy Spirit",c:"who shall be called Emmanuel",d:"spoken of by the prophets"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:215,question:"“How is it that you, a Jew, ask a drink of me, a woman of 	Samaria?” The speaker was surprised because",option:{a:"Jesus was God and not human",b:"the Jews could only buy water from Samaria",c:"the Jews had no dealings with Samaria",d:"it was unlawful for a man to receive water from a woman"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:216,question:"Jesus said “Not everyone who says to me ‘Lord, Lord,’ shall enter into the kingdom of heaven, but he who",option:{a:"hears the word of God”.",b:"prays and fasts’",c:"prophesies in my name”",d:"does the will of my father”"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:217,question:"According to Jesus, a disciple must not",option:{a:"hate his parents and family",b:"bear his own cross",c:"be a poor man",d:"count the cost"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:218,question:"Instead of being unnecessarily anxious about life and the affairs of this world, Jesus taught us to",option:{a:"relax our minds and wait for the manna from above",b:"seek first the kingdom of God and its righteousness",c:"seek water baptism and qualify for divine healing",d:"repent of our sins and preach the gospel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:219,question:"According to Jesus, the seventy disciples who returned from a successful missionary work should rejoice because",option:{a:"the demons were subject to them",b:"the sick were healed through their ministry",c:"the lame walked just at their command",d:"their names were written in heaven"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:220,question:"The seeds that fell among thorns represent those who hear the word of God but lose it because",option:{a:"they refuse to be baptized in water",b:"their parental background does not allow them to believe",c:"the cares of the world and delight in riches choke the word",d:"the unbelievers do not permit new converts to receive the word"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:221,question:"The rich man who ignored the needs of Lazarus lacked",option:{a:"a sense of proportion",b:"parental care",c:"human sympathy",d:"spiritual contentment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:222,question:"Abiding in Christ’s love demands that we",option:{a:"have hope for the future",b:"keep His commandments",c:"imitate one another",d:"manifest the peace of God"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:223,question:"According to Jesus, a good shepherd lays down his life for the sheep but a hireling",option:{a:"sells them off for personal profit",b:"abandons the sheep in the face of danger",c:"protects some of the sheep leaving others to danger",d:"asks for better pay before doing his work."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:224,question:"The arrest of Jesus by his enemies was",option:{a:"an accident of faith",b:"a result of his tough teaching",c:"a fulfilment of the scriptures",d:"a ploy to see his miraculous powers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:225,question:"The final trial of Jesus was presided over by",option:{a:"Herod",b:"Caiaphas",c:"the High Priest",d:"Pilate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:226,question:"Before his ascension, Jesus commissioned his disciples to go to all nations and",option:{a:"cast out demons",b:"heal the sick",c:"raise the dead",d:"make disciples of them"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:227,question:"The experience which totally changed Paul’s focus in life was his",option:{a:"witnessing the martyrdom of Stephen",b:"determination to wipe out the church",c:"participation in the council of Jerusalem",d:"encounter with Jesus on the road to Damascus"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:228,question:"Herod persecuted the early church because he was",option:{a:"opposed to the Apostles’ teaching",b:"impressed by his growing popularity after killing James",c:"unhappy that the Jewish leaders were not doing enough havoc to the apostles",d:"asserting the extended powers granted him Rome."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:229,question:"One of the early Christians who sold his property and gave the money to the apostles was",option:{a:"Barnabas",b:"Stephen",c:"Barabbas",d:"Matthias"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:230,question:"Which of the following was not characteristic of the Early Church?",option:{a:"Constant change in leadership",b:"Devotion to the teachings of the apostles",c:"Breaking bread in members’ homes",d:"Communal fellowship"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:231,question:"“Father forgive them for they know not what they do” was the prayer said by",option:{a:"Philip",b:"Peter",c:"Paul",d:"Stephen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:232,question:"Paul argued that Jesus died for us while we were yet sinners in order to",option:{a:"prove that he was not an ordinary man",b:"show Gods’ love for sinful man",c:"warn us to desist from sin",d:"give us power to possess the earth"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:233,question:"Paul, in Romans, taught that Christians are Abraham’s descendants by",option:{a:"grace",b:"faith",c:"circumcision",d:"law"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:234,question:"According to Romans, when civil authorities punish evil doers, they do so as the",option:{a:"agents of God’s wrath",b:"supervisory authority",c:"agents of the darkness of this world",d:"representatives of angelic powers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:235,question:"Paul said he was not fit to be called an apostle because he",option:{a:"was not called like the others",b:"was not a Jew",c:"persecuted the Early Church",d:"was only a distributor of letters"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:236,question:"In Romans, Paul admonished Christians, in their dealings with secular powers, to",option:{a:"reject all secular laws",b:"pray for the leaders",c:"refuse to pay tax to them",d:"respect the authorities"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:237,question:"Paul taught that by our common faith in Jesus and baptism, the difference between Jews and Gentiles has become",option:{a:"permanent",b:"temporal",c:"irrelevant",d:"real"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:238,question:"The Philippians’ gifts to Paul were for",option:{a:"the growth of the church",b:"his sustenance",c:"distribution to the saints",d:"other Christian prisoners"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:239,question:"Which of the following does not relate to the new life in Christ?",option:{a:"Baptism",b:"Circumcision",c:"Grace of God",d:"Faith"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:240,question:"Paul taught the Colossians that the relationship between wives and their husbands should be as",option:{a:"is fitting in the Lord",b:"the culture demands",c:"is written in the law",d:"the husband commands"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:241,question:"At the coming of the Lord, unbelievers will",option:{a:"be condemned",b:"have a desolate land",c:"be hit by famine",d:"die in divine war"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:242,question:"Paul compares the manifestations of spiritual gifts in individual members of the Church to the",option:{a:"unity of the human body",b:"rights of the individual members of the Church",c:"rights of the different parts of the body",d:"unity of the Church"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:243,question:"Paul wrote to the Thessalonians about idleness because he 	learnt that they were",option:{a:"among the idlest people in Asia",b:"forcing Christians to work in the Church",c:"unwilling to give offerings",d:"expecting the second coming of Christ"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:244,question:"Paul appealed to Philemon to forgive Onesimus on the basis of",option:{a:"equality",b:"righteousness",c:"love",d:"faith"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:245,question:"James recommends the anointing oil of the elders because such anointing",option:{a:"prepares the sick for his last journey",b:"makes the sick holy and righteous",c:"promotes physical recovery",d:"ensures forgiveness to the sick"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:246,question:"Peter advised his fellow elders to tend the flock of God that was in their charge",option:{a:"with care",b:"willingly",c:"by example",d:"domineeringly"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"}],t={subject:e,status:200,total:50,data:a};export{a as data,t as default,o as status,e as subject,s as total};
